Allen Ginsberg Collection
Allen Ginsberg Collection
1962-1997
Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.
1 folder (SC)
Papers of the American poet. Correspondence, poems, photographs.
149340
Biographical History
Allen Ginsberg (1926-1997) was an American poet and -- with William S. Burroughs and Jack Kerouac -- a seminal member of the Beat Generation. Ginsberg is best known for the poem Howl (1956), celebrating his fellow Beats and attacking what he saw as the destructive forces of materialism and conformity in the United States at the time.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Allen Ginsberg Papers consists of correspondence and writings. Correspondence consists of outgoing items to Imamu Amiri Baraka (Leroi Jones), Marshall Bean, Robert Wilson, and Geoffrey Hazard. The Wilson letter, written shortly before Ginsberg's death, also includes two photographs. Writings include two signed and dated holograph poems and three signed typescript poems.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged in alphabetical order. Writings are subdivided by type and then arranged alphabetically by title.
Related Material
See also the
Allen Ginsberg Interview
. also has Beat-related books, pamphlets, serials and other items are inour Rare Books holdings. Please search for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Radicalism; Baraka, Amiri, 1934-; Bean, Marshall.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Hazard, Geoffrey.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Beat Generation (Group of writers); Bohemianism -- United States.; Literature, Experimental.; Poets, American.; Letters (correspondence); Photographs.; Poems.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1969.
1997 letter purchased, 2013.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Baraka, Imamu Amiri (LeRoi Jones), Apr. 24, 1962; 1 postcard (Sc 24)
  - Bean, Marshall, 1965; 1966; 2 letters (Sc 24)
  - Hazard, Geoffrey, undated; 1 postcard (Sc 24)
  - Wilson, Robert, Feb 1997; letter, handwritten, and two photographs signed and captioned by Ginsberg (Sc 24)
    Purchase, 2013.
- Writings
  - Poems, handwritten, signed
    - "Guru", May, 1965 (Sc 24)
    - "The masters of silent illumination.. ." (untitled), 1966 (Sc 24)
  - Poems, typed, signed
    - "Malest Cornifici Tuo Catullo" (Sc 24)
    - "Message" (Sc 24)
    - "The Shrouded Stranger" (Sc 24)